<thesaurus xmlns="http://marklogic.com/xdmp/thesaurus">
    <metadata>
        <package-name>Thesaurus</package-name>
        <date>2004-08-17</date>
        <version>1.0</version>
        <authors>
            <author>Mark Logic</author>
        </authors>
        <description>
            This thesaurus is based on the wordnet thesaurus included in the
            MyThes-1.0 software. A small script was written to extract
            valid xml from the data files.
        </description>
        <copyright>
            This thesaurus is provided at no cost by Mark Logic
            Corporation, subject to the enclosed restrictions. Mark Logic
            Corporation disclaims any liability resulting directly or indirectly
            from any access or use, whether proper or improper, of (a) the
            information contained in this document or (b) functionality in Mark
            Logic or other application software that makes use of information
            contained in this document. Any reproduction or modification of all
            or part of the information contained in this document is governed by
            and must be accompanied by the attached license and copyright
            notices.
        </copyright>
        <sources>
            <source>
                <package-name>MyThes-1.0</package-name>
                <author>Kevin B. Hendricks</author>
                <copyright>
                    Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
                    modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
                    are met:

                    1. Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
                    notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.

                    2. Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright
                    notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the
                    documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.

                    3. All modifications to the source code must be clearly marked as
                    such. Binary redistributions based on modified source code
                    must be clearly marked as modified versions in the documentation
                    and/or other materials provided with the distribution.

                    THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY KEVIN B. HENDRICKS AND CONTRIBUTORS
                    ``AS IS'' AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT
                    LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS
                    FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL
                    KEVIN B. HENDRICKS OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT,
                    INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING,
                    BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES;
                    LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION)
                    HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT
                    LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY
                    OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF
                    SUCH DAMAGE.
                </copyright>
                <sources>
                    <source>
                        <package-name>WordNet Database</package-name>
                        <author>Princeton University</author>
                        <copyright>
                            This software and database is being provided to you, the LICENSEE,
                            by Princeton University under the following license. By obtaining,
                            using and/or copying this software and database, you agree that you
                            have read, understood, and will comply with these terms and
                            conditions.:

                            Permission to use, copy, modify and distribute this software and
                            database and its documentation for any purpose and without fee or
                            royalty is hereby granted, provided that you agree to comply with
                            the following copyright notice and statements, including the
                            disclaimer, and that the same appear on ALL copies of the software,
                            database and documentation, including modifications that you make
                            for internal use or for distribution.

                            WordNet 1.6 Copyright 1997 by Princeton University. All rights
                            reserved.

                            THIS SOFTWARE AND DATABASE IS PROVIDED "AS IS" AND PRINCETON
                            UNIVERSITY MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES, EXPRESS OR
                            IMPLIED. BY WAY OF EXAMPLE, BUT NOT LIMITATION, PRINCETON
                            UNIVERSITY MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES OF MERCHANT-
                            ABILITY OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE OR THAT THE USE OF THE
                            LICENSED SOFTWARE, DATABASE OR DOCUMENTATION WILL NOT INFRINGE ANY
                            THIRD PARTY PATENTS, COPYRIGHTS, TRADEMARKS OR OTHER RIGHTS.

                            The name of Princeton University or Princeton may not be used in
                            advertising or publicity pertaining to distribution of the software
                            and/or database. Title to copyright in this software, database and
                            any associated documentation shall at all times remain with
                            Princeton University and LICENSEE agrees to preserve same.
                        </copyright>
                    </source>
                </sources>
            </source>
        </sources>
    </metadata>
    <entry>
        <term>bird</term>
        <part-of-speech>noun</part-of-speech>
        <synonym>
            <term>maya</term>
        </synonym>
        <synonym>
            <term>ibon</term>
        </synonym>
        <synonym>
            <term>bayung</term>
        </synonym>
        <synonym>
            <term>gamgam</term>
        </synonym>
        <synonym>
            <term>parrot</term>
        </synonym>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <term>Car</term>
        <part-of-speech>noun</part-of-speech>
        <synonym>
            <term>Ford</term>
            <part-of-speech>noun</part-of-speech>
        </synonym>
        <synonym>
            <term>automobile</term>
            <part-of-speech>noun</part-of-speech>
        </synonym>
        <synonym>
            <term>Fiat</term>
            <part-of-speech>noun</part-of-speech>
        </synonym>
    </entry>
</thesaurus>
